University Executive Committee meeting minutes and related documents
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections
University Executive Committee meeting minutes and related documents
1982-2003
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections Phone: 513-745-4821 http://www.xavier.edu/cm/archives
Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio). University Executive Committee
3 linear feet (8 bound volumes and 3 boxes)
Meeting minutes and related documents of the University Executive Committee at Xavier University.
XUA-13
History of University Executive Committee
The University Executive Committee, an advisory committee to the university president, underwent various name changes through the years. It's date on inception is not clear, but is was in existence at least since 1982. It discontinued in 2003.
This is a brief history of various advisory committees to the Xavier University president. Through the years these committees have undergone changes in name and in committee composition. The main purpose of these committees was to advise the president on university matters.The University Executive Committee existed since at least August 4, 1982. It probably existed earlier, but there is no record of it in the archives prior to 1982. It was made up of the president of the university and the vice presidents. Other university officers were invited to attend its meetings as they were needed. The University Executive Committee should be distinguished from the Executive Committee of the Board of Trustees which is composed of Board members, officers of the Corporation and, in more recent times, the chairs of the Board's standing committees.For the first two meetings of the 1982-83 academic year, this committee was called "The Executive Council (see the 8/4/82 and 8/18/82 minutes). After that it was named "The Executive Committee" in all of its minutes, until August 24, 1990, when it became the "University Executive Committee." The University Executive Committee ceased to exist on August 25, 2003, when it was replaced by the "President's Administrative Council." The President's Administrative Council consisted of approximately 25 members. It was phased out in 2009 and was replaced by "The President's Cabinet" which had been created two years earlier. The President's Cabinet was formed in August 2007. It consisted of 12 members plus the deans of the Colleges who attended as non-voting members. For two years from 2007 to 2009, the President's Administrative Council and the President's Cabinet existed together. As of August, 2012, the President's Cabinet still exists.
Scope and Content
Meeting minutes and related content from the Xavier University Executive Committee.
Statement of Arrangement
Collection arranged as transferred from the President's Office. Bound volumes are arranged chronologically. Folders which may supplement or provide new information are arranged chronologically in a separate series.
Series 1. University Executive Committee minutes bound volumes
Series 2. University Executive Committee minutes folders
Separated Material
Electronic files of meeting minutes of the Xavier Executive Committee can be found in the archives N Drive under the Folder "Committees."
Restrictions on Access
Restricted access. Please contact the Xavier University Archives staff.
Acquisition Information
Materials dated prior to 8/19/1986 were transferred to the Xavier University Archives in Summer, 1992 from the Academic Vice President's office. Otherwise materials were transferred from the Xavier University President's office on August 27, 2012 to the archives.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects:
Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio)--Administration; Xavier University (Cincinnati,Ohio)--Planning
Detailed Description of The Collection
- Series 1: University Executive Committee Bound Volumes, 1986-1995
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 1986-1987 (Volume 1)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 1987-1988 (Volume 2)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 1988-1990 (Volume 3)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 1990-1991 (Volume 4)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 1991-1992 (Volume 5)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 1992-1993 (Volume 6)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 1993-1994 (Volume 7)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 1994-1995 (Volume 8)
- Series 2: University Executive Committee Folders, 1982-1996
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 1982-1996 (Box 1)
    - Minutes, August 4, 1982 to June 19, 1985, 1982-1985 (Folder 1)
    - Minutes, August 28, 1985 to June 25, 1986, 1985-1986 (Folder 2)
    - Minutes, 1986 to 1990: Supplementary Materials, 1986-1990 (Folder 3)
    - Minutes, June 5, 1995 to December 18, 1995, 1995 June-December (Folder 4)
    - Minutes, January 4, 1996 to May 28, 1996, 1996 January-May (Folder 5)
    - Minutes, June 3, 1996 to December 30, 1996, 1996 June-December (Folder 6)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 1997-2000 (Box 2)
    - Minutes, 1977 January-May (Folder 7)
    - Minutes, 1997 June-December (Folder 8)
    - Minutes, 1998 January-May (Folder 9)
    - Minutes, 1998 June-September (Folder 10)
    - Minutes, 1998-1999 (Folder 11)
    - Minutes, 1999 February-May (Folder 12)
    - Minutes, 1999 July-December (Folder 13)
    - Minutes, 2000 January-June (Folder 14)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 2000-2003 (Box 3)
    - Minutes, 2000-2001 (Folder 15)
    - Minutes, 2001 February-May (Folder 16)
    - Minutes, 2001 June-August (Folder 17)
    - Minutes, 2001 September-December (Folder 18)
    - Minutes, 2001-2002 (Folder 19)
    - Minutes, 2002 June-September (Folder 20)
    - Minutes, 2002-2003 (Folder 21)
    - Minutes, 2003 March-July (Folder 22)